Giovanni Pires da Silva

in linkedin.com/in/giovannipds

github.com/giovannipds

giovannipds@gmail.com

+55 54 99968-0088

Summary

Hi! My name is Giovanni and I'm a software engineer with 17 years career. I'm PRETTY GOOD at frontend but also got skills at backend. I also got honored by more than 9 awards already.

I have developed more than 100 sites and probably given maintenance to 300. I've started my career as Graphic Designer, Webmaster, Web Developer, Frontend, Backend, Full Stack. I went to 3 societies and passed by 11 companies. From a design studio to advertising agencies, digital agencies, software houses and startups.

I have made many graphic design, image processing, 3D, web design/development, CMSs, ecommerces, portals, APIs, hybrid/native apps, animations/TV commercials and probably many other things. I really love to DEVELOP! Internet, apps and modern technologies. I know D/X/HTML/5, CSS 2.1/3, Flash/Flex, ActionScript 2/3, PHP, jQuery, OpenCart, WordPress, Swift, JSON/XML, Smarty, CodeIgniter, MySQL, Photoshop/Illustrator, Angular/Ionic/TypeScript, Git, Grunt/Gulp, Bootstrap, SASS/LESS/Stylus/styled components and MANY other stuff. I've hosted in many places and know some AWS services.

My favorite stuffs nowadays are React, JavaScript, CSS, Laravel, Figma, HTML5 and Next.js. I got a very good eye to detail and user experience. I also love information architecture and learning! If we got a problem, I'm pretty sure we'll figure it out! I like to work as a team, but I'm good individually too.

I'm currently looking for the next step of career. I invested some time at my LinkedIn profile, so if you'd like to read more about me, please take a moment. Thank you!

Experience

GAD_

Principal Software Engineer

SomosGAD_

Aug 2019 - Jun 2020 (11 months)

First and main developer of the company, worked full-time at Dale, the startup's principal and unique product, a multi-tenant platform to the world of soccer – like a Netflix for soccer/entertainment. Our main customers were River Plate and Universidad de Chile (La Ú) – but we've also made business with other soccer teams, like Colo-Colo, Independiente and others. I was responsible for any IT-related decisions, software development, infrastructure, team acquirement, deploy, replication, frontend, backend, API development, payment integrations, etc. Worked a lot with React and Next.js, Laravel, MySQL, Vercel (formerly Now) and many, many AWS cloud services, like: CloudFront, Elastic Transcoder, RDS, Route 53, S3, Certificate Manager, CloudFormation, Elastic Beanstalk, Elemental MediaConvert and Elemental MediaPackage, IAM, Lambda and Step Functions. Dale is probably one of the products I've made that I'm most proud of.



Frontend Engineer

Cheerful

Jan 2020 - Feb 2020 (2 months)



Cashier

Padel Pro

Feb 2019 - Nov 2019 (10 months)



Full Stack Engineer

Balcão Balcão

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019 (9 months)

While at Ezoom, I got the opportunity to join to this project, a startup that connects ecommerces to package delivery through national bus routes - more or less a freight system. After an analyst guidance, I became the Full Stack Engineer of Balcão Balcão, being the one and only engineer responsible for all the API development and app development of two company apps, one for the stores management and other for customer package tracking. I've also made the first company's plugin for OpenCart and mentor another developer to finish the company's website. My work at Balcão Balcão was mainly with Laravel PHP, MySQL, Angular, TypeScript, Ionic, OpenCart and also with CodeIgniter, with an own framework of Ezoom. Balcão Balcão app and API are also one of the best work I've done so far and I'm very proud of having done it.



Software Engineer

Ezoom Agency

Mar 2018 - Feb 2019 (9 months)

I worked at Ezoom as a full stack software developer, being the first company's programmer to join Ezoom Lab, an space exclusively to startups, where I've started working at LinkLei and later on at Balcão Balcão. Besides these two great projects, I had the honor of being part of the hiring selection, interviews and tests. Another incredible project that I've made was a native app in Swift with augmented reality, which I've needed to learn the language in less than a month to solve it, saving up to 5 thousand dollars for the company. Besides that, I also helped to solve problems that needed speaking in English, by any means. We've also made a challenge Angular x React to evaluate the languages resources and decide the future of the company. Here was also the first time I've worked with LESS and started using Visual Studio Code.



Web Developer

LinkLei

Mar 2018 - Jun 2018 (4 months)



Senior Frontend Web Developer

TÁTUM Business Comm

Nov 2017 - Feb 2018 (4 months)



Mobile App Development Instructor

Cadmax Technical and Vocational School Sep 2017 - Nov 2017 (3 months)



Frontend Web Developer

GET Agency
May 2017 - Jul 2017 (3 months)



Co-Founder / Web Developer

X Company
Aug 2016 - Apr 2017 (9 months)



Founder / Web Developer

Bombin8
Oct 2015 - Apr 2017 (1 year 7 months)



Frontend Developer

FDD

Mar 2015 - May 2015 (3 months)



Full Stack Engineer

Weecom Digital Agency
Apr 2013 - Aug 2014 (1 year 5 months)



Frontend Web Developer

Alvo Global

Mar 2011 - Aug 2012 (1 year 6 months)



Co-Founder / Frontend Developer

Graphia Web

May 2009 - Oct 2010 (1 year 6 months)



Web Developer

Alvo Global

Feb 2008 - May 2009 (1 year 4 months)



Web Developer

Graphia Design

Jan 2005 - Jan 2008 (3 years 1 month)

Webmaster

Graphia Design 2003 - Dec 2004 (1 year)

Junior Graphic Designer

Graphia Design 2002 - Dec 2004 (2 years)

Education



UCS - University of Caxias do Sul
Bachelor's degree, Digital Technologies
2011 - 2012 (incomplete)



Grupo Uniftec - Centro Universitário e Faculdades Technologist, Analysis and Systems Development

Licences & Certifications

- OmniStack Week 11 Rocketseat
- The Future of Technology in Business Cia do Micro
- FOSSDay Bento Gonçalves 2018 FOSSDay
- The Complete ARKit Course Build 11 Augmented Reality Apps Udemy
- Tchelinux Porto Alegre 2017 Tchelinux
- Tchelinux Caxias do Sul 2017 Tchelinux
- KingHost Connection 2017/2 KingHost
- Tchelinux Bento Gonçalves 2017 Tchelinux
- 19th Locaweb Meeting Locaweb
- KingHost Connection 2015 KingHost
- 16th Locaweb Meeting of Internet Professionals Locaweb
- Lecture "Just Get it Done" with Tiago Mattos WBF Logistics
- Online Course for Website Creation "Web for Designers" Arteccom

Volunteer Experience

Meetanços · Tchelinux · Google Developer Group (GDG) Serra Gaúcha · uva64

Honors & Awards

- Winner of the Frontend Test Front in Floripa 2018 Geek Hunter
- Site of the Day Banana Café Awwwards
- Website of the Day Banana Café CSS Design Awards
- Website of the Day Weecom CSS Design Awards
- SOTD (Site of the Day) Banana Café CSS Winner
- SOTD (Site of the Day) Weecom CSS Winner
- Featured Banana Café CSS Awards
- Featured Weecom CSS Awards
- Winner of the Day Banana Café CSSREEL

Skills

```
CSS • JavaScript • React • Frontend • Development • Web • Photoshop • Figma • Laravel •
Next.js • PHP • HTML5 • SASS • Ionic • Git • jQuery • Programming • MySQL • Node •
Communication • Problem Solving • User Experience • TypeScript • Animation (+)
```

Recommendations

"Giovanni is a highly skilled developer, who has the ability to work with the same skill on both Back End and Front End. He is the type of employee that brings energy and focus to the team, shares knowledge and makes the workplace enjoyable. I hope we can work together in future projects."

Danner Terra - Software Engineer / Laravel Spring Node React

"Excellent professional, very knowledgeable in the best web development technologies such as React, Next, Ionic, Javascript, CSS. Great developer ;)"

Rober Zanotto Guerra - CTO | Software Engineer | LinkLei

"I met Giovanni on another project before we were colleagues at Ezoom, when we organized a Django Girls in our local community in Bento Gonçalves, Serra Gaúcha. Giovanni has outstanding experience in developing Web Applications, mainly with PHP and Javascript. But it doesn't stop there: when there are new challenges, with new technologies he learns them and manages to overcome those challenges. Also, he is committed to the projects in which he participates. Another remarkable quality of Giovanni is the question of sharing his knowledge. He was my mentor when I started to develop and I learned a lot with him in both companies where we worked together. Also, he participates in technology groups and events, always wanting to help others and evangelizing new technologies. I would be glad to work with him again."

Camilo Cunha de Azevedo - Software Developer at Lendflow